Unmask the truth.
The Batman is a crime, mystery, thriller film directed by Matt Reeves.
In his second year of fighting crime, Batman uncovers corruption in Gotham City that
connects to his own family while facing a serial killer known as the Riddler.
Bruce Wayne / The Batman, played by Robert Pattinson.
Selina Kyle, played by Zoë Kravitz.
Lt. James Gordon, played by Jeffrey Wright.
Oz / The Penguin, played by Colin Farrell.
The Riddler, played by Paul Dano.
Carmine Falcone, played by John Turturro.
The Batman is a 2022 American superhero film based
on the DC Comics character Batman.
Directed by Matt Reeves from a screenplay he wrote with Peter
Craig, it is a reboot of the Batman film franchise.
Robert Pattinson stars as Bruce Wayne / Batman alongside Zoë Kravitz, Paul Dano, Jeffrey
Wright, John Turturro, Peter Sarsgaard, Andy Serkis, and Colin Farrell.
The film sees Batman, in his second year fighting crime in Gotham City, uncover corruption with ties to his own
family while pursuing the Riddler (Dano), a mysterious serial killer targeting the city's elite.
Reeves and Dylan Clark produced the film for DC Films and Warner Bros.
A Batman film for the DC Extended Universe (DCEU) franchise was announced in
October 2014, with Ben Affleck starring as the character.
He signed on to also direct, produce, and co-write The Batman by 2016, but had
reservations about the project and stepped down in January 2017.
Reeves took over the following month and reworked the story, removing the DCEU connections to focus on a
younger version of the character earlier in his vigilante career compared to Affleck's portrayal.
Reeves worked on the script with Craig and Mattson Tomlin, and sought to explore Batman's detective aspects more than previous films, drawing inspiration from
the films of Alfred Hitchcock and the New Hollywood era, and comics such as "Year One" (1987), The Long Halloween (1996–97), and Ego (2000).
Following Affleck's departure as the star in January 2019, Pattinson was
cast in May, and additional actors joined later that year.
Filming took place from January 2020 to March 2021 and was halted
for several months due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The production occurred throughout the United Kingdom, including on
location in England and Scotland, as well as at Warner Bros.
Studios Leavesden.
Cinematographer Greig Fraser shot the film with Industrial Light & Magic's StageCraft virtual
production technology, while Michael Giacchino composed the musical score.
The film has over 1,500 visual effects shots and is one
of the longest superhero films ever made.
After facing multiple delays caused by the COVID-19 pandemic, The Batman was theatrically released in the
United States on March 4, 2022, three days after premiering at the Lincoln Center in New York City.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for Reeves's approach, the performances of Pattinson and
Kravitz, and the cinematography and score, although the tone, runtime, and third act received some criticism.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $772 million worldwide against a $185–200 million budget, making it
the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2022 and Warner Bros.'s highest-grossing pandemic release.
Its financial performance set several pandemic-era box office
records, particularly for IMAX screenings.
The film was nominated for three Academy Awards and
received numerous other accolades.
The Batman is intended to start a trilogy and the
"Batman Epic Crime Saga" franchise.
A sequel, The Batman: Part II, is scheduled for release on October 1, 2027, while a spin-off
television series starring Farrell, The Penguin, debuted on HBO in late 2024.
The film explores themes of police, psychopath, secret
identity, crime fighter, superhero.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.